你们想听听我改编的一些
Hey, would you like to hear some songs I've rewritten
促进儿童对自然科学的产生兴趣的歌吗
to get children interested in the hard sciences?
-好啊  -你不是吧
- Sure. - Really?
是啊  我喜欢音乐  也喜欢科学
Yeah. Well, I like music, I like science,
我还喜欢嘲笑谢尔顿  开唱吧
I like making fun of Sheldon. Hit it.
* 有名科学家有理论 *
* There was a scientist who had a theory *
原曲来自儿歌 《Bingo was his name-o》
还有拍手跳过音的小游戏
* 他叫詹姆斯·克拉克·麦克斯韦哟 *
* And James Clerk Maxwell was his name-o *
*詹  女  母  其  斤*
* J-a-m-e-s *
* 克  扌立  十  兄 *
* C-l-e-r-k *
* 空格 夂十兄其斤韦
* Space M-A-X-W-E-L-L *
* 他叫詹姆斯·克拉克·麦克斯韦哟 *
* And James Clerk Maxwell was his name-o *
* 有名科学家有个理论 *
* There was a scientist who had a theory *
* 他叫詹姆斯·克拉克·麦克斯韦哟 *
* And James Clerk Maxwell was his name-o *
*  女  母  其  斤 *
* A-m-e-s *
行了  行了  我们明白了
Uh, okay, okay. Uh, we-we get it.
或许你会比较喜欢这首
Perhaps you'd prefer this one.
* 可爱蜘蛛  不是昆虫哟 *
* The itsy bitsy spider is not an insect at all *
来自经典儿歌《Itsy Bitsy Spider》
开头两句与《蝴蝶蝴蝶真美丽》一样
* 脚长了八只 *
* Because it has eight legs *
* 身体有两段 *
* And two body parts *
蛮酷的  谢尔顿
That's pretty cool, Sheldon.
谢谢
Thank you.
你俩有谁认识碧昂丝[女歌手]吗
Do either of you know Beyonce?
我想让她也来支持这计划
I'd love her to get behind it.
你们知道宇航局最近在弄的
You guys know the new Discovery class missions
-发现计划吗  -知道啊
- that NASA's been working on? - Yeah.
宇航局投入成本由低到高分别是
发现计划  新疆界计划  探索计划  旗舰计划
他们想要在里面加入一段来自地球的讯息
Well, they're looking to include a message from Earth
以防哪天真碰见了外星生命
in case one of them is encountered by alien life.
我遇见外星人的时候  我发现到
When I encountered alien life, I-I discovered
最重要的事情就是别抢了他的专座
that the key thing was not to sit in its spot.
你吸地球空气还得依赖呼吸器[哮喘]
All right, you can't breathe our air without an inhaler,
他对地球的坚果过敏
he's allergic to Earth nuts,
还好意思说我外星人呢
but I'm the alien.
反正我和少数几位科学家
Anyway, I'm among a handful of scientists
被要求提交一份方案
that have been asked to submit a design proposal
设计讯息本身及其传达系统
for the message and its delivery system.
-太棒了  -恭喜啊
- Excellent. - Congratulations.
所以我在想你们有谁
And I was wondering if any of you guys
愿意来帮忙我呢
would like to help me do it.
废话  当然愿意啦  你有什么构想了吗
Are you kidding? Yes. What did you have in mind?
我来告诉你应该怎么做
I'll tell you exactly what you should do:
避免对地球人感知模式的先入为主
avoid the presumption of the Terran sensory input paradigm.
完全正确
Yeah, absolutely.
你需要有个能用更多元化
You need a device capable of delivering information
感知传播形式来投放讯息的仪器
across a wide range of perceptual modalities.
任何智能生物最少都需要有
Any intelligent organism would at the very least need
知晓物体在空间中所在位置的能力
the ability to locate the position of objects in space.
所以最理想的星际沟通方式应该是触觉
So the ideal interstellar lingua franca would be haptic.
改造一台三维触感传输器好让它能
Ooh, how about a 3-D tactile communicator rigged
多类型感知传输
for cross-sensory transposition?
跟我料想的一模一样
Exactly what I expected.
两个人把想法强灌到我脑里
Two people forcing their ideas on me
而只有一位绅士愿意问我
and only one gentleman who could be bothered
我有什么构想
to ask me what my thoughts were.
你们俩出局了  恭喜  莱纳德
You two are out. Congratulations, Leonard,
你入围了
you're on the team.
我妈咪培养了个绅士
My mommy raised a gentleman.
谢谢你过来
Hey. Thanks for coming by.
我很乐意来帮忙啊
Yeah. I'm excited to help.
我不是不愿意叫上另外两个
I would have included the others, but...
可你也知道他们来了会怎么样
you know exactly what would've happened.
他们会抢过这个计划  还对我们颐指气使
They would've taken over the project and bossed us around.
我懂
I get it.
就今早吧
Uh, just this morning,
谢尔顿不允许我在早餐"浆果与坚果"里
Sheldon wouldn't let me put almond milk on my Grape-Nuts
知名美国早餐麦片品名
其实并不含任何浆果或坚果
加杏仁奶  他说理论这算坚果大战
because he said it was a theoretical nut conflict.
你应该叫他少多管闲事
You should have told him to mind his own business.
是啊  这句话比我当时回答的那句好多了
Yeah. That's better than what I did say, which was,
我回了"好吧  我配气泡水吃吧"
"Fine, I'll eat them with club soda."
他们凭啥觉得自己可以永远掌控一切啊
What makes them think they're always in charge of everything?
他们是雄性帝王[α]人格嘛
Mmm, they're alpha males.
那我们俩算啥
What does that make us?
我们可以当宰相[β]  一人之下万人之上
We could be betas. They're second in charge.
这样听起来还行
Okay, that sounds good.
或者我们可以是死老百姓[Ω]
Or we could be omegas.
任帝王将相蹂躏玩弄
They get pushed around by the alphas and the betas.
听起来的确很像我们
Okay, that sounds like us.
都无所谓了  这里没有帝王
Whatever. There's no alphas here,
而这是你的项目
and this is your project.
你来做主  你想怎么开始
You're in charge. How do you want to start?
我不知道  你想怎么开始呢
I don't know. How do you want to start?
不知道啊
I don't know.
我们应该打给谢尔顿跟霍华德吗
Should we call Sheldon and Howard?
不用  我们可以自己搞定
No. We can do this by ourselves.
好的  行  你想怎么开始
Okay. Great. How do you want to start?
我不知道  那你想怎么开始
I don't know. How do you want to start?
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
我敢说你一开始是为了嘲笑我
I bet that started off as a joke,
但敲完第三下时  你发现
but by the third one you realized
有一股莫名的愉悦感涌上心头
there was something strangely enjoyable about it.
是啊  搞得人家都想再来一次了
Yeah, I kind of want to do it again.
我不建议这么做  你这辈子都会戒不掉
I don't recommend it. You'll be doing it the rest of your life.
如果你是来找莱纳德  他去库萨帕里家了
Anyway, if you're looking for Leonard, he's with Koothrappali.
不是  我其实是来找你谈谈
Uh, no, I actually came to talk to you.
这么好啊
How nice.
给你提供几个我有兴趣的话题
Here are some topics that interest me:
量子力学  火车  旗帜
quantum mechanics, trains, flags...
不是不是  是来谈我的演艺事业
No, no. It's about my acting career.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
这不在话题名单之上
That's not on the list.
等等  别这样
Oh, wait. No.
不如我们各退一步
How about we split the difference
改来聊聊为什么奥地利是大公国
and discuss why Austria was an archduchy
而不是普通公国
and not just a regular duchy.
听我说  事情是这样的
Okay, look, here's the thing.
我喜欢做医药销售  干得也不错
I like pharmaceutical sales--it's going great--
但我有一个电影的试镜
but I have an audition for a movie,
如果我得到那个角色  可能会失去现在的一切
and if I get it, it could screw everything up.
我完全知道你该怎么做
I know exactly what you should do.
很可惜  我不能告诉你
Unfortunately, I cannot tell you.
为什么
Well, why?
我在尝试改过自新
I'm attempting to turn over a new leaf.
今天早些时候  有人向我指出
Earlier today, it was pointed out to me
我常常将自己的想法强加于人
that I tend to force my ideas on people.
你真的不打算告诉我吗
You're really not gonna tell me?
不  时机已过火车已离站
No, that train has left the station.
现在我们有两种玩法
Now, we can play this one of two ways.
你可以说"火车  再说说"
You can say, "Trains, tell me more,"
或...
or...
你也可以那样看着我
you can just look at me like that
我就会开始说
and I'll start.
你在里面鼓捣啥呢
What's going on in here?
我在做分子鸡尾酒
I am making molecular cocktails.
这个小球其实就是大都会鸡尾酒
This sphere is actually a cosmopolitan.
那要怎么喝呢
How do you drink it?
直接放进嘴里  然后像挤青春痘那样挤爆它
Oh, just put it in your mouth and pop it like a zit.
我还是喝啤酒吧
I think I'll have a beer.
先跟我一起拍张照
First take a picture with me.
为什么
Why?
我和拉杰一直在说要
Well, Raj and I always talked about learning
一起学做这样的鸡尾酒
how to make cocktails like this together,
现在我学会了  我要把照片放分享网站上
so I taught myself and I'm putting this on Instagram
好让他看见  觉得自己很屎
so he can see it and feel like a turd.
笑一个
Say cheese.
是因为航天探测器的项目他没让你参与吗
Is this about the space probe he's working on without you?
那还用说  肯定是啊
You betcha. The very one.
霍华德  你是成年人了
Howard, you're grown men.
你们几个用不着干什么事都在一起
You guys don't have to do everything together.
我知道  所以我今晚跟你待着啊
I know. That's why I'm spending tonight with you.
你是想让拉杰难过
Trying to hurt Raj's feelings.
跟我的宝贝一起惩罚他
With my honeybunch.
你真幼稚
You're being childish.
不  他才是
No. He is.
没错  我是有支配性人格
So I have a dominant personality.
我们大家都知道
We all know that.
抱歉  我们都知道什么
I'm sorry. What do we know?
在社交团体中
In social groupings,
话事权总是自然而然落在我手里
I just naturally wind up in charge.
你别误会  我不是要质疑你
Don't take this the wrong way,
但你是吃了多少颗这种小酒球啊
but how many of these little booze balls have you had?
你认为我不是领导吗
You don't think I'm a leader?
我开玩笑啦  你当然是啊
I was kidding. Of course you are.
对啊  我想改也改不过来
Right. I couldn't change if I wanted to.
你最好不要改  因为我喜欢这样的你
You better not change, because I love who you are.
你鼓捣完后  需要我帮忙清理吗
Now, will you need help cleaning all this up when you're done
或是你一个人全包了
or can you do it all by yourself?
我全包了
All by myself.
这才是我的大领导嘛
There's my big boss man.
通常在火车头前面
So, often on the front of the locomotive
有一个大铁楔
is a large iron wedge
用来清理铁轨上的东西
for clearing objects off the tracks.
通常俗称"排障器"[抓牛器]
Now, while commonly known as a cowcatcher,
最早在火车头装这个
是为了把铁轨上散步的牛或障碍赶走
我喜欢更确切的叫法"爆牛器"
I prefer the more accurate "Cow exploder."
好吧  谢尔顿  我问你个问题
Okay. Sheldon, let me ask you a question.
如果我在火车站
If I was at a train station
有一辆火车可以载我去我现在的工作
and one train could take me to my current job
另一辆可以载我去一部电影的试镜
and the other train could take me to an audition for a movie,
那我应该上哪辆火车呢
which train should I get on?
你是在利用火车来骗我给你建议吗
Are you using trains to trick me into giving you advice?
不是
No.
那就可以说
All right, then.
你应该上第三辆火车
You should take a third train
去参加电影试镜
where you audition for the movie
但先别着急做职业上的抉择
but hold off on making a career decision
等了解更多情况再说
until you have more information.
你说得有道理
You're right.
我在担心一件根本还没发生的事
I'm worried about something that hasn't even happened yet.
你真是位智者
You are a wise man.
佩妮  谁更聪明  是智者
Well, Penny, who's smarter: the wise man
还是向智者寻求建议的那个人
or the person who comes to him for advice?
我猜你说得对
Oh, I guess you're right.
或许还真是懂得寻求建议的人
Maybe it is the person who asks.
错  是智者
No, it's the wise man.
不然他干嘛叫智者
That's why he's called the wise man.
你知道我怎么知道的吗
You know how I know that?
我就是智者
I'm the wise man.
抱歉  我刚才在想什么啊
I'm sorry. What was I thinking?
出于好奇问一句
Uh, just out of curiosity,
这件事你干嘛不问莱纳德意见呢
why didn't you ask Leonard for advice about this?
因为我早就知道他会说什么
'Cause I already know what he'll say.
"这个那个  总之你不该去"
"Wah, wah, wah, you shouldn't do it."
跟他本人在这似的
It's just like he's here!
人类之前已经尝试过将讯息投放到太空中
Okay, so we know that previous attempts to send a message into space,
就像旅行者上的金唱片
like the Golden Record on Voyager,
骂声一片
were heavily criticized.
外星人只有做一台唱机出来
Well, aliens could only play the Golden Record
才能播放金唱片
if they figured out how to build a record player.
不过公平地说  我看着ET用一台学习玩具
Although, to be fair, I watched E.T. build a telephone
和一把伞  做了一台电话机
out of a Speak & Spell and an umbrella.
那小家伙就像棕色皮肤的马盖先
Dude was like a little brown MacGyver.
美国90年代连续剧中的男主角
擅长用普通生活用品作为工具
如果E.T.真实存在  会大有帮助
That would be more helpful if E.T. were real.
电影里它快死的时候  我的感情是真实的
Well, my feelings were real when he was about to die.
天啊  还有它躺在台子上  他们电击它
My God, when he's on the table and they use the paddles on him.
它全身都变白了
And he's all white.
他们把他放进袋子  拉上拉链
They zip him up in that bag.
格蒂一直在哭
And Gertie can't stop crying.
花都枯萎了
The flower dies.
-够了  我们换个话题吧  -好的
- Okay, let's talk about something else.- All right.
听起来我们需要一种简单的沟通方式
So it-it sounds like we need a way to communicate that's simple.
而且不需要外部机器
And doesn't require outside machinery
就可以直接读取
to be built to access it.
这也是一个问题  因为我们根本不知道
It's also a problem because we don't even know
找到这个东西的外星人是否有视觉
if the aliens who find this can see.
他们可能会用
I mean, they might communicate
和我们完全不同的方式进行交流
in a totally different way than us.
就像我的小狗生我气时
Like when my dog is mad at me,
她的表达方式是尿我拖鞋上
she tells me by peeing in my slippers.
这还真是一个很好的例子
That's actually a valid example.
动物就会用气味来传达信息
Animals do deliver messages through scent.
蜜蜂通过舞蹈来互相交流
Bees talk to each other by dancing.
鲸鱼有自己的鲸鱼歌
Whales have their songs.
佩妮有20种翻白眼的方式
Penny has about 20 different ways of rolling her eyes
每种白眼都代表不同的意思
that each mean something different.
好了  总结起来就是
Okay, so, what it sounds like is,
我们需要的是
what we want is a device
一种不光是用视觉  还能透过其他感知方式
that can deliver a message through not only sight,
传递讯息的装置
but other senses, as well.
任何宇宙文明都应该具备的
The most basic sense that any space-faring civilization
最基本的感知就是触觉了
would have to possess is touch.
我们应该设计一个可以播放视频
We could make a video-playing device
同时能把讯息转化到
that simultaneously translates the information
可触摸媒介上的装置
into a tactile medium.
我们只需要装配一台三维交流系统装置就行了
All we have to do is rig up a 3-D communication system!
我们完全可以办到
We-we can totally do that!
我知道
I know!
实在太棒了
This is great!
-还有件事你知道吗  -什么
- Yeah, you know what else it is? - What?
这和谢尔顿  霍华德之前说的完全一样
Exactly what Sheldon and Howard said.
多谢你在我拖鞋里撒的这泡尿
Well, thank you for peeing in my slippers.
* 这是猛虎的眼睛 *
* It's the eye of the tiger *
* 这是蝙蝠的耳朵 *
* It's the ear of the bat *
* 这是鲶鱼的胡须 *
* It's the whiskers of the catfish *
* 和海象的... *
* And the walrus... *
等等  不是说你的歌烂  它的确很烂
Hang on. Not that your song isn't terrible-- it is...
但是你提到蝙蝠  怎么能忘掉声纳呢
...but how do you mention bats and leave out sonar?
人家还没唱完呢
You didn't let me finish.
* 既然提到了蝙蝠*
* And also regarding the bat *
* 它还有声纳 *
* It has sonar. *
好啊
Hello.
我说
Look,
我知道你们俩不高兴  但我们讨论过了
I know you guys are upset, but we've talked about it,
我们认为你们的加入
and we think it'd be beneficial
对这个项目很有好处
for you to be part of the project.
哎哟哟  你听到了吗  谢尔顿
Well, well, well, did you hear that, Sheldon?
抱歉  我刚才很专心在想
I'm sorry. I was trying to think of what rhymes
"食蚁兽的鼻子"和什么词押韵
with "Nose of the aardvark."
我们希望你俩加入这个项目
We want you back on the project with us.
哎哟哟  你听到了吗  霍华德
Well, well, well, did you hear that, Howard?
我们承认
Look, we admit it.
你俩的点子非常不错
The idea that you guys came up with was really good,
我也很希望得到你们的帮助
and I'd love your help.
我想要你说出这些话对也不容易吧
I suppose it couldn't have been easy for you to say that.
是不容易  所以你们愿意吗
It wasn't, so... are you in?
-愿意  -当然
- Certainly. - Sure.
太好了
Great.
既然大家意见都一致了
Now that we're all on the same page,
今晚我们就一起开始工作吧
let's get together tonight and work on it.
"今晚一起来"
"Get together tonight"?
莱纳德  不要老是想掌控全局
Leonard, stop trying to control everything,
让可怜的拉杰也有机会做个决定好吗
and give poor Raj a chance to come up with what we should do.
说吧  拉杰
Go ahead, Raj.
我觉得我们现在就开始吧
Okay, I think we should do it right now.
-我今晚比较方便  -好吧
- Tonight works better for me. - Okay.
好了  只是个试镜而已
Okay, it's just an audition.
我干嘛要紧张呢
Why am I nervous?
也许这是一件好事
Maybe it's a good thing.
紧张代表我很渴望这角色
Just means I want it.
我一定能得到这个角色的
And I can have it.
这种感觉倍儿爽
This feels right.
我当初干嘛要放弃演艺事业呢
Why did I ever give this up?
往事一幕一幕涌上心头
I'm starting to remember.
我想尝试一种新的方式
So, I'd like to try a technique
让大家享受平等的待遇
where no one gets steamrolled.
你们说话时
When you talk,
不要一开口就提出新点子
instead of bringing up a new idea,
要尊重别人之前的发言  加上"如你所说"
respect what was just said by building on it.
如你所说
Uh, building on that...
我们应该叫个外卖
...we should order dinner.
你这话哪一点算是如他所说呀
How is that building on what he just said?
如谢尔顿所说  我想吃中餐
Building on what Sheldon said, I could go for Chinese.
等等  如莱纳德所说
Hang on. Building on what Leonard said,
完全没人是接我所说的啊
no one built on what I said.
如你所说的"如你所说"
Building on "building on that,"
科罗拉多有家新开的自选披萨店
there's a new build-your-own pizza place on Colorado.
如你所说  我想提醒你
Building on that, I'd like to remind you,
我有乳糖不耐症
I'm lactose intolerant.
我看过菜单了  里面有豆酪可选
I saw the menu. They have soy cheese.
你没有说"如你所说"  你输了
You didn't say "building on." You're out!
这又不是"我说你做"游戏
It's not Simon Says.
你的重点错了  谢尔顿
Yeah, you're missing the point, Sheldon.
你输了  你也输了
You're out, and you're out.
我赢了  谁想吃披萨
I win! Who wants pizza?
佩妮
Penny?
好久没看到你来试镜了
I haven't seen you auditioning in a while.
我找了份医药销售代表的工作
Yeah, uh, I got a job as a pharmaceutical sales rep.
你不演戏了吗
You quit acting?
算是吧
Well, kind of.
不过现在我需要演
But now I get to act like
心脏发炎只是无关痛痒的副作用而已
inflamed heart is only a "Mild side effect."
我听说干这一行可以赚不少钱呢
I heard you can make good money doing that.
是啊  待遇还不错  但我有时会怀念演戏
Yeah, it's going okay, but I do miss this sometimes.
真的吗
Really?
我告诉你  我可是烦透了这种倍受屈辱
'Cause I got to tell you, I am so sick of the humiliation
被人当块肉般对待的生活
and being treated like a piece of meat.
切尔西
Chelsea?
祝我好运吧
Wish me luck.
他们一定会喜欢你
They're gonna love you.
我听说她都快40岁了  全身都修整过
I heard she's pushing 40 and everything's fake.
这谣言是我传出去的
Yeah. I started that rumor.
我们已经讨论出了投放讯息的设备
Okay, since we agree on the delivery system for the message,
现在可以讨论要投放什么讯息了
maybe we should talk about what the message could be.
我认为要能显示出地球人的模样
Well, I think we should show what earthlings look like.
他们在先驱者号探测器上装的是
The plaque they sent up on the Pioneer probe
一对裸男女的画像
had a drawing of a naked man and woman on it.
我对那种不感冒
Yeah, I never cared for that.
简直是在告诉掠夺种族
It's advertising to predator races
我们是有多软弱多好蹂躏
just how soft and squishy we are.
蹂躏你自己去
Squeeze yourself!
听了别不高兴
Oh, don't be offended.
你明知道我们四人当中
You know, of the four of us,
你最有小鲜肉的质感了
you have the most veal-like consistency.
或许有方法可以表明我们没有侵略的意愿
Well, maybe there's a way to appear nonaggressive,
但还是有保护我们自己的能力
but also be able to protect ourselves if necessary.
比如微笑着一手挥手
Like smiling and waving with one hand,
另一只手里拎个砍下来的虎头
but the other hand holding the severed head of a tiger.
你想投放一条放冷箭的讯息
You want to send a passive-aggressive message
到太空里吗
out into the universe?
太可笑了
That's ridiculous.
你说的放冷箭是指
Oh, you mean passive-aggressive
发张你和你老婆吃着本属于我的
like posting pictures of you and your wife
大都会鸡尾酒球的那种行为吗
eating cosmopolitan balls that you know belong in my mouth?
也许霍华德说的放冷箭是指
Perhaps Howard meant passive-aggressive
一开始请我们大家来帮忙你的项目
like asking our group to help on your project,
可是最终只选了莱纳德一个人
and then only choosing Leonard.
抱歉伤你们感情了
Look, I'm sorry I hurt your feelings,
可你们俩都太强势
but you do have strong personalities
话事权总是会被你们抢过去
and always end up taking over.
也没有总是啊
It's not always.
那次去漫展
What about when we went to Comic-Con
我们办成赫特人贾巴
and dressed like Jabba the Hutt?
《星球大战》角色
基本就是一条大型脑满肠肥样鼻涕虫
你扮贾巴的脑袋
You got to be Jabba's head,
我只能扮死肥鼻涕虫下半身
and I got to be his fat slug butt.
我们看起来超赞
We looked great.
你还让个男人坐我身上
You let a guy sit on me.
他扮的是莱亚公主
He was dressed as Princess Leia.
合照效果特好
It made a nice picture.
我只是说拉杰和我有时候感觉被排挤了
I'm just saying, sometimes Raj and I feel pushed aside.
比如你带谢尔顿去了德克萨斯
Yeah. Like when you took Sheldon to Texas
带他参观了宇航局
and showed him all around NASA--
都没想到请莱纳德和我去啊
you didn't even think to ask me and Leonard.
你们说得对
You know what? You're right.
我应该邀请你们的
I should have asked you.
如果他邀请了  立马答应
Yeah, and if he does ask you, go.
老炫酷了
It's amazing.
如果要说被排挤
Okay, and if we're talking about being left out of things,
你们去了天行者牧场也没带我们啊
you guys went to Skywalker Ranch without us.
那地方我也诚意推荐
Oh, I recommend that, too.
简直是梦幻之旅啊
That was a magical experience!
等等
Wait a minute.
谢尔顿跟詹姆斯·厄尔·琼斯待了一天
Sheldon spent a whole day with James Earl Jones
都没告诉我们
and never told any of us.
还真是
I sure did.
天了噜
Oh, my goodness!
从贾巴脑袋到跟黑武士吃雪糕
Well, from Jabba's head to ice cream with Darth Vader,
我这一路走来精彩纷呈啊
I'm having a heck of a ride.
你看
Yeah, look,
明显由我说了算的时候都有好事发生
clearly, good things happen when I'm in charge.
孩子们现在何不退下
Now, why don't you boys step aside,
让朕将此项目一举击破
let me knock this project out?
谢尔顿  不是你做主
Sheldon, you're not in charge.
拉杰做主
Raj is in charge.
莱纳德  究竟谁做主
Leonard, who's really in charge?
是做主的人  还是任命谁做主的人
The person in charge, or those who put him in charge?
他说得对
He's right.
你想想  其实我们都能做主
If you think about it, we're all in charge.
不  做主的人才是主...
No, the guy in charge is in...
怎么每个人都不懂这种问题呢
Why is everyone so bad at these?!
整段经历都让我记起
I mean, the whole experience reminded me
为什么我会恨那个世界
about how much I hated about that world.
那种焦虑压抑  负能量爆棚
You-you know, the anxiety, the depression, the negativity.
我不想有那种感觉
I don't want to feel those things.
我想把药卖给有那种感觉的人
I want to sell drugs to people who feel those things.
难以置信你居然这么干脆地
I can't believe you got up and walked out
放弃大电影的试镜
of an audition for a big movie.
是啊
I did.
我进去了  念了段台词
I-I mean, I walked in, read for the part,
然后卡壳了  就马上走人了
then stunk up the place, but then I walked right out.
很高兴能看到你对工作有了新的认识
Well, I'm glad you have a new appreciation for your job.
确实有新感悟
I do, and you know, I don't think
我还没好好谢过你帮我找到这份工作
I've ever thanked you properly for helping me get it.
好好谢还是压根没谢过
Properly, at all.
都是我从未听过的言语
It's just words I've never heard.
谢谢你
Well, thank you.
你是个好朋友  改变了我的人生
You're a good friend, and you changed my life.
不客气
You're welcome.
既然你现在也挣大钱了
Hey, now that you're making some real money,
可以请你的朋友出去吃顿大餐表示感谢啊
maybe you can take your friend out for a nice thank-you dinner.
当然
Sure.
或许也应该带上你另一个朋友
And you probably have to invite your other friend
因为听者有份
'cause she overheard you talking about it,
不带她就太不对了
and it would be awkward to exclude her.
好的
Okay.
现在就去吧
How about now?
行吧
All right.
别忘带钱包
Don't forget your wallet.
我...
I...
来自地球的问候
Greetings from planet Earth.
在半人马座阿尔法星左转既是
Just turn left at Alpha Centauri.
想错过都难
You can't miss it.
《星际迷航记》中的瓦肯人举手礼
即"生生不息  繁荣昌盛"